Andrew Jayasinghe

andrewjay915@gmail.com

+1 236-885-1672

6655 Napier Street, Burnaby, BC V5B 2C2

https://andrewjayasinghe.github.io/resume/

Summary

First year student at the British Columbia Institute of Technology pursuing a Diploma in Computer Information Technology with experience in Windows/Linux Systems Administration; Object Oriented Program construction using python; Web Applications development using front end Angular API as well as back end Node.js framework, which include handling MongoDB & TSQL Database posts and requests, and experience in Constructing LAN networks using virtualization software.

Developed an understanding in the following:

Business Process Development.

CSS, HTML and WordPress

VMWare Workstation

VirtualBox

> Python

Bash scripting

> TSQL

MongoDB

Node.js & Angular Java script frameworks RStudio

> Team Cohesion

> Active listening

➤ GitHub Collaboration

➤ Network Configuration

Education & Training

BRITISH COLUMBIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY - Vancouver, BC (September 2019 - September 2021) Computer Information Technology Diploma (First Year)

CANADIAN RED CROSS Emergency First Aid & CPR/AED level A Certification - Vancouver, BC (*Cert No:* 101394775)

COLOMBO INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL - Colombo, Sri Lanka (September 2014 - September 2016) Pearson Edexcel Advance Level Certification (Physics, Mathematics, Chemistry)

Experience

Head Starts Child Care – Surrey, BC (January 2020)

A Local Day Care Service in Surrey, BC http://www.headstartschildcare.com/

- 1) <u>Web Development & Content management:</u> Responsible for the Initial Construction and the ongoing maintenance and Content management of the client domain above.
 - Assisted the Client in Selecting a suitable Hosting service and content management system.
 - Constructed the website using WordPress according to client specifications which increased it's mobile responsiveness and ease of access to information.
 - Currently Updating the client website with relevant information/material as needed by the client.

BCIT Project Work - Vancouver, Canada (Sep 2019 - Present)

All Team & individual projects completed as a part of the Diploma program till date

- 1) <u>Self Published Website</u>: Designed and published the https://andrewjayasinghe.github.io/resume/ domain/site on GitHub.
 - Used Bootstrap, jQuery, HTML and CSS which increased the customizability, responsiveness of the website and made the website mobile friendly.
 - Used GitHub as a collaboration platform and as a free hosting service in order to obtain feedback and collaborate on best/effective coding practices.
- 2) <u>Python Audio Library/Audio Player:</u> Designed and Developed an Audio Player/Audio Library using Python and Object-Oriented Programming concepts as a team project.
 - Used OOP Concepts and UML to design the player according to industry standards.
 - Used Python to code and construct as well as postman and flask to test the program.
 - Used the test-driven development method in the construction on the program and obtained an understanding of the industry coding standard.

BCIT Recreation Services - Vancouver, Canada (Sep 2019 - Present)

The Department that is responsible for the all recreational facilities & equipment, staff, events & services that are conducted by BCIT.

- 1) <u>Weight Room Attendant:</u> Responsible For the overall Safety and cleanliness of the Weight room and it's equipment while on shift, handling site tours and answering questions regarding the proper use of the gym equipment as well as making sure that the BCIT code of conduct is maintained within the facility.
 - Ensuring that there's a welcoming atmosphere at the gym by being warm & cheerful
 - Cleaning of all cardio machines and wiping down the weights in order to maintain a clean facility.
 - 2) Intramural Staff: Responsible for the safety of participants while ensuring good sportsmanship.
 - Ensuring that the players were aware of their scores & fouls which ensured smooth gameplay.
 - Experience as a referee and de-escalation of tense situations during games.

The Church of Jesus Christ Of Latter-Day Saints - Manila, Philippines (May 2017 - May 2019)

A Christian Religious organization that is focused on helping humanity through the teachings of Jesus.

- 1) <u>Volunteer Full-time Missionary:</u> Served as a missionary by learning the local language (Tagalog) to teach English and about the teachings of Jesus Christ to help the impoverished communities in manila.
 - Studied the Tagalog language and Conducted English Classes for groups of 20 individuals
 - Ensured the safety and well-being of a team of 6 missionaries of various nationalities.
 - Taught and Served the locals and helped them with infrastructure development when possible.
 - Conducted an Entrepreneurship Seminar in Collaboration with a local university (University of Caloocan City) for the benefit of the students in the business program.
 - Creating and maintaining reports and assessments regarding all missionaries within the group of missionaries and those they teach.

^{*}References available upon request.